James P. Hurst Papers VHP2004/6
CCSU Veterans History Project
James P. Hurst Paper
Bulk, 1943-1945
1943-1945, 2004
VHP2004/6
CCSU Veterans History Project
5.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
Hurst, James P.
Biographical Note
James Hurst, a native of Andover, Connecticut enlisted in the Army Air Force on March 27, 1943 at the age of seventeen. James began his military career as a Pilot Cadet his first step towards achieving his dream of becoming a United States Air Force pilot. During World War II James was trained to fly both B-25 and B-24 bombers among other aircraft. He served as a member of the 782nd Bomb Squadron and the 465th Bomb Group and attained the rank of 1st Lieutenant. James Hurst earned four Air Medals and the Distinguished Flying Cross.
Scope Note
This collection details James Hurst’s experiences and training during his enlistment in World War II as well as the years following. A taped interview was conducted on February 16, 2004 at James’ home by Eileen Hurst. The collection consists of the taped interview and reproductions of photographs. The materials cover James’ experiences from 1943 thru 1945, providing evidence of American troop combat activity, American flight training and deployment, and U.S. military moral and courage under fire.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged based on content and material type into 2 series:
Series I, Personal papers
Series II, Multi-media
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
United States. Army Air Forces. Bombardment Group (Heavy), 465th.; B-24 bomber; Canosa di Puglia (Italy); Maxwell Field (Ala.); Mitchell bomber; Naples (Italy); Palmer Field (S.C.); Turner Field (Atlanta, Ga.); World War II - - Personal Narrative, American; World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- Italy; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations, American.
- Series I: Personal Papers, 1943-1945
  - Synopsis of James Hurst’s oral history interview, February 16, 2004; 2004/6.I.1
- Series II: Multi-Media
  - Subseries A: Still images, 1943-1945
    - Portrait of James P. Hurst in Army Air corps uniform with wings, 1943-1945; 2004/6.II.2
    - Group photograph of Flight crew wearing bomber jackets and helmets with goggles. James Hurst standing, second from right, 1943-1945; 2004/6.II.3
    - James Hurst in an electrically heated flight suit., 1943-1945; 2004/6.II.4
    - Group portrait of Flight crew posing near aircraft. James P. Hurst (standing, right), 1943-1945; 2004/6.II.1
  - Subseries B: Moving images
    - Oral History Interview with James P. Hurst, Feb. 16, 2004; 2004/6.IIb.1 (Disk DVD VHP 2004/6, Box VHP Interview 1)
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      Interview video also available online.
      Streaming Video